TEA HOUSE
IRON MONKEY
It's so cold,
how can the refugees stand it?
There's been lots of natural
disasters recently.
And even more corrupt officials.
Another arrives today.
He's well known for his evil ways.
Do you think Iron Monkey will appear?
THE GOVERNMENT HOUSE
OF CHEKIANG
Follow me... this way.
Please have some dim sum first.
Masters, the midnight snack is ready.
Enough! Not while we're listening
for any movement on the roof.
Masters, help yourselves.
"HONESTY AND JUSTICE FOR ALL"
If the food isn't on time,
forget it.
Clumsy fool. Leave us!
We're trying to catch Iron Monkey.
I heard the monks were brought
from the Shaolin Temple.
Who knows?
Let's have a midnight snack.
Stop squashing me, you girls.
Don't keep climbing
in and out of bed.
Do you want Iron Monkey
to know my treasure is down there?
- Come out!
- I just want my share.
Do you really want
to divide it up now?
Quick, hide!
Sir.
It's the head of security, Fox.
I've got abalone and ginseng soup
for you and your wives.
Do you think now is the time?
Don't touch it
or I'll deduct half a year's salary!
I wouldn't dare.
On the roof!
There's something happening up there!
Shoot!
Not even a bird can get in.
If Iron Monkey comes,
we'll turn him into a hedgehog!
It is I, Iron Monkey!
Master.
Stand to, men! Stand to!
Stay calm.
There are too many of you.
Get out of the way!
Master, it's us.
Get out of the way, you men!
Catch him!
You men stay put.
He wants to lead us into a trap.
Stay at your posts.
Yes, sir.
You can't escape this time,
Iron Monkey.
You aren't monks!
- You dare mock us Shaolin?
- To hell with Shaolin.
You call yourselves Shaolin monks?
I'll teach you impostors a lesson!
Good always triumphs over evil!
You call yourself good?
Aiding corruption is never good.
You know it's wrong, so don't do it!
He got in!
Honey, help me escape
and I'll give you your share.
- It's too late now!
- Go to hell!
Officer Cheng, set the trap off!
I am too cunning, you can't beat me!
See you later!
Lower the net!
You're a lucky man, sir.
You said the net was impenetrable!
Go and take a look!
- Go and check the roof.
- Yes, sir.
Shaolin!
- Be careful.
- It's very high.
Damned Iron Monkey.
I'm not going to buy a coffin
before I spend all this money.
I'll thank my lucky stars.
Your Excellency,
I've posted guards everywhere,
I don't think he'll get in again.
What is this?
Shark fin? I told you not to eat it!
- No, sir.
- Deduct your salary.
I broke the bowl accidentally...
Your Excellency,
there's no sign of him.
Everyone will be deducted a month's
salary to go to a reward.
If you can't catch him,
the money is mine!
Damn you all, fools!
What company are you from?
Fox, you're smart, don't blink.
Your Excellency, Iron Monkey!
Thank you for your donation
to the flood appeal.
"Thank you for your jewels,
your donation to the disaster.
"Because of your kind donation,
I won't kill you."
You've already taken my life!
Iron Monkey is wanted again.
Let's see if this officer
can get him.
Mr Fox, those who haven't been caught
by the government must thank God.
If he's caught, then we'll thank God.
This is a little gift
sent to you by my master.
He intends to make
the Islamic Temple into a brothel.
When the application is submitted,
perhaps His Excellency
would look on it favourably.
Say, we can make money together.
How could we make a deal without you?
His Excellency is in a bad mood.
I have to bargain with him directly.
Take the gifts back or I won't be
able to repay it if any is lost.
Iron...
Don't mention the name,
it's bad luck.
One month of our salary
has been deducted.
We have to pay our own medical bills.
Thank you for the money,
which solves our problem.
Come and thank Mr Chan.
Thank you.
PA CHO HALL
- Old man, is your throat sore?
- Yes.
- Do you also have diarrhoea?
All right, give me your hand.
What's wrong with me, Doctor?
You are sexually overactive.
Your kidney is weak.
You are always eating shark's fin
and ginseng. Such food makes you hot.
You are too weak
to afford such nutritious foods.
How can nutritious foods
cause illness?
How is this possible?
What should I do, Doctor?
I'm telling you the truth.
It's making you weak.
One hundred taels.
One hundred taels!
I don't have that much, Doctor.
Don't worry, old man. You can go,
I won't take a penny from you.
Thank you.
Why is he free
and yet you charge me so much?
You're a rich man,
so your medicine is expensive.
If you can't afford it, I'll
prescribe cheaper medicines for you.
Me, not afford it? Pay him.
You really do cure him.
Thank you.
You're looking better.
- Doctor Yang.
- Master Fox.
Good business.
So many patients in your clinic.
You are such a versatile doctor.
Most of them come from Hoi Ning. They
have the plague as well as flooding.
They've been walking for three days.
What? The plague?
It's horrible!
Oh, here's Miss Orchid.
Obstipantia, disinfectants, check the
herb list, don't make any mistakes.
It's as busy as a restaurant in here.
Miss Orchid.
Master Fox. What's wrong with you?
Nothing. You're getting rich
from such a prosperous business.
I heard Iron Monkey was arrested,
is that true?
I got him in my Pallium Stance.
He couldn't move.
I gave him another severe blow
before he could do anything.
That's what happened to him?
Yeah, that's what happened.
That's great
that you caught Iron Monkey.
So many of my colleagues
had been hurt,
I gave him a chance to mend his ways
and I let him go.
Master Fox, every time you set a trap
to catch Iron Monkey,
you always let him go free.
You're giving him too many chances.
I guess I owe him.
He appeared two years ago
when I was transferred to this town.
One day I'll tear his mask off!
Master Fox,
if you feel the heat, let go.
So hot!
What's wrong with a light touch?
Were you the hooker from the brothel?
We're a little short of girls.
Come and join us.
Get lost!
How dare you!
How dare you be so rude here!
Find your hookers elsewhere.
Are you Master Fox?
We are friends, please forgive...
This clinic is under my protection.
No vulgar behaviour is allowed here!
Master Fox, show me some respect.
If you do,
I'll give you 100 pieces of gold.
How dare you bribe me so openly!
Take him to the cells!
How dare you! I'll sue you...
You won't even get to see
the governor without my say-so.
Go!
"CHINESE HERBS CURE DISEASE"
Thank you, Master Fox.
Master Fox, take this medicine
for your fellow soldiers.
Apply it to their wounds twice daily
and they'll be cured in 3-4 days.
- Thank you.
- Take care.
The new officer is coming,
I'm sure Iron Monkey will come
and make trouble.
I hope he doesn't appear again.
Master Fox, be careful.
- Good morning, Dr Yang.
- Good morning.
Mr Fox... Are you thinking
he may be Iron Monkey?
Everyone seems to be Iron Monkey
in my eyes.
PA CHO HALL
Cook it for longer, then the abalone
will taste much better.
You're lying, that's not abalone,
it's just some tree bark.
A monkey screeching?
It's real gold!
Iron Monkey has come to save us.
Give it to me. I'm in charge.
Who threw that?
It's Iron Monkey.
He's too greedy.
I'm not greedy. Let's share it
amongst us. Thank you, Iron Monkey.
It's so cold...
The building's falling down!
No, it's gold,
it must be Iron Monkey.
Thank you, Iron Monkey.
What's up? Work harder!
All these refugees are so cheap. I'll
get some strong men tomorrow instead!
Work harder, or do you want a beating?
We haven't eaten all day.
Right, my dog's hungry too!
Don't expect any pity.
I'll employ someone else tomorrow!
A dead rat!
Who's there? Who threw that?
Bullying kids, revolting!
Iron Monkey really exists!
Iron Monkey the Merciful.
Iron Monkey?
Let me help you.
You still come out
in this awful weather.
The new officer, Cheng Pak Fong,
arrests people for no reason.
He is beating the people up.
I will visit him tomorrow
and teach him a lesson.
Vegetables and tofu for every meal.
It's so boring, Master!
Are you really so poor you have to
take up an official post?
If we can't find the money,
we wouldn't even have this to eat.
I may as well go back to the brothel.
It's hard work supporting
all of my nine mistresses.
OK, I'll open the storeroom
and sell it all. Then we can leave.
Make sure you get a good price,
then we'll leave.
All you think about is food.
Boy, come here.
Sir, I don't have any money left.
Your salary is worthless.
Follow me to the storeroom.
Sir, it is a letter from the capital.
Sir, is it a good position?
The State Governor is coming
to investigate me.
If Iron Monkey appears,
then we're in trouble.
Why are you still standing there?
Arrest Iron Monkey. Arrest anyone
who's remotely connected to him!
Yes, sir.
"HUANG THE INVINCIBLE'S
LAST APPRENTICE"
- What move are you practising?
- The Monkey's Palm.
- Really?
- Yes.
- Right, let's go.
- Why?
You said the word 'monkey'.
The word 'monkey' brings trouble.
Take the sign down.
Arrest those whose name is Monkey.
Still want to run away?
You look like a monkey,
take him away.
Sir, since when is a sneeze
an of fence?
You act like a monkey. Take him away!
Monkey and date powder!
What are you selling?
Don't mention the word 'monkey'.
Look for yourself.
You won't even say what you're
selling? You must be scared.
Take him away!
- Hold on tight.
- Yes, Dad.
Dad.
Pei-hung, you're old enough
to walk on your own now!
Recite the herb list.
Chiretta, good for blood.
Ginseng, good for respiration.
Crocodile, to cure catarrh.
Lizard to treat poisoning. Tin-tsi...
Tin-tsi...
To cure swelling, you fool.
Tin-tsi to cure swelling, you fool.
- Boss.
- Master, Wong.
The herbs are all ready.
I'm going back to Fushan tomorrow.
Please send them to my lodgings.
No problem.
That's all you've made
from a whole day's work?
Do you think this is a charity house?
If you have nothing, you must steal.
Watch yourselves.
Who did that?
Pei-hung, honest people
don't do such sneaky things.
Shoot at me?
Go back to the inn
and practise foot work for two hours.
Go pick his pocket.
What are you doing picking pockets
at your age?
I'll never do it again, sir.
I'll let you go this time,
but you'd better not do it again.
You are lucky.
I have to practise for two hours.
What's wrong with practising?
What's so bad about stealing?
Is it good to teach you a lesson?
- He could be Iron Monkey.
- I think you're right.
Dad.
Stop! You're disturbing the peace.
Come with us.
He stole my stuff.
I didn't see that,
but I did see you fight. This way.
Why are they only arresting them?
"HONESTY AND JUSTICE FOR ALL"
Don't act so pitifully!
Behind your ignorant faces,
any one of you may be
the terrible Iron Monkey.
Speak up! Show yourself!
Be sensible.
I'll release anyone who speaks up.
I'll release those who give me
any information about Iron Monkey.
Speak out!
Sir, there's a monkey
flashing his backside at you.
How dare you disgrace this court
like this!
I hate indecency! Take him away
and punish him severely!
Sir, you will be eating
monkey's brain tonight.
Don't tell my mistresses.
If no-one confesses,
you will all be fined 50 taels.
50 taels? Is that all?
What do you expect?
Under the circumstances,
each of you is fined 500 taels!
No, please don't do that!
If you can't pay,
it's the brand for you!
Where are you now, Iron Monkey?
If you were a real hero,
you would come out.
You look pissed off.
Execute!
Dad! You can't do this
without any proof, Your Excellency.
How dare you!
He presumes to tell you
how to govern, sir.
How dare you be so rude to me at such
a young age. Give him 30 lashes!
He is just a child, sir.
If you plead for him,
you will be a suspect.
Your Excellency, he is too young.
He can't take it.
If he wants to escape the punishment,
he has to pay, otherwise punish him!
Don't move!
Your Excellency, you are punishing
the innocent, Iron Monkey's here.
If it wasn't for my cunning, you'd
never have come out during the day.
You're trapped! Positions, gun troop!
Kill him!
He's gone outside! Go after him!
If this is how you behave,
you'd best resign!
Your eyebrows! They're gone!
What? They brought me good luck.
Now I'm going to be unlucky.
Iron Monkey,
I arrest you to save the innocent.
Who are you?
- You're good.
- So are you.
My foot.
It's so exciting.
They're such good Kung Fu masters.
- Put the ladders up.
- Yes, sir!
It's a kid.
- Pei-hung, are you OK?
- Yes, I'm fine.
You're a great fighter, hero.
- My father's well known in...
- Boy. He has such a big mouth.
He is as powerful as Iron Monkey.
Sir, Iron Monkey was here,
so we're proved innocent.
May we leave now?
No! You could well be his partner.
No-one will be released
until he is caught.
Very wise, sir.
Let us go. Show mercy, please, sir.
Sir, if I, Wong Kei-ying,
take responsibility for catching
Iron Monkey, will you let them go?
- Wong Kei-ying from Canton?
- Yes, sir.
Nice to meet you.
Wong Kei-ying is very famous.
More famous than me?
Wong Kei-ying,
I'll show mercy this time.
Arrest Iron Monkey
before seven days are up.
I will keep your son here
in the meantime.
You're detaining my son?
Your belongings too!
With your son in jail,
you won't escape.
Court adjourned!
- Are you going alone?
- I'll arrest Iron Monkey soon.
Don't worry, I'll look after him.
Thank you.
Set them free.
He's helping arrest Iron Monkey?
What a bastard!
Come this way.
The noodles are delicious.
Another bowl of noodles. I'm sure
you'll enjoy such delicious noodles.
Noodles, please.
Are you Wong Kei-ying
who fought Iron Monkey?
I am.
Shame on you.
I won't sell you anything. Go!
- Why?
- Ask the fortune teller.
Why?
Can I have two buns, please?
I won't sell you anything, bastard.
Who are you calling bastard?
I'll pay.
I won't sell it to you, if you want it
you'll have to steal it.
I'll take my money.
Thief! Wong Kei-ying is a thief!
He's robbing my money! Thief!
Bastard!
Do you want a bun? Five taels each.
So expensive?
It's not expensive.
I'm risking my life to sell to you.
I quit! I'm sorry.
Hot buns.
I'll take 20 buns.
Thanks.
They can't tell right from wrong.
Honest people don't do sneaky things.
Except this time.
Luckily Pei-hung isn't around.
That fell on the ground, are you sure
you want to eat it, my friend?
I'm so hungry, I haven't eaten in two
days. I don't care if it's dirty.
I don't know why,
but they refuse to sell me food here.
You seem to be a stranger here.
Don't eat that.
- Come and have some soup.
- Soup?
Sorry about my stomach.
I'm so hungry. If it had been rice...
You are so slow.
You are too slow at frying.
When can I eat?
I'm sorry, Master Wong,
I'm a bit slow.
- Not at all.
- Be patient, it will be ready soon.
Master Wong,
we grow a special kind of chilli,
which we call sweating, it's so hot.
Even a little makes your nose run.
You must try some later.
Water.
Are you thirsty?
Don't drink water, there's the soup.
I wasn't thirsty, I was just cleaning
my mouth so the soup tastes better.
Remember to wear an apron the next
time you want to clean your mouth.
Let me help you, Miss Ho.
I can prepare some dishes
from home for you.
Golden chicken, it smells delicious!
Master Wong, you are a great cook.
My wife passed away a while ago,
so I do all the housework myself.
Master Wong, we are honoured
to have you cooking for us.
It's only Cantonese food,
please try some.
Well, let us Northerners
and Southerners sit down together.
Let me make some Northern
speciality noodles for you.
The first slice, God's blessing.
The second slice,
no more natural disasters.
The third, peace and prosperity.
- Cheers!
The wine brings friends together.
To all the friends we've known.
Cheers.
- Cheers.
Master Wong, what is worrying you?
I am thinking of my son.
I have all this great food here.
But my son is behind bars and I don't
know if he's eaten at all.
I don't know if anyone
is looking after him.
Dr Yang, have you heard
of Iron Monkey?
Yes, I've heard the talk.
Do you want to find him?
If I catch him,
I'll chop his head off!
Is he your enemy?
The governor is keeping my son
in jail until I arrest Iron Monkey.
If I can't catch him, my son
and I can never go back to Fushan.
Both the good and bad are against us.
- What's your son's name?
- Wong Pei-hung.
Wong Pei-hung.
I won't bother you any further.
The quicker I catch Iron Monkey,
the quicker I see my son.
Dr Yang, Miss Ho,
I'll repay you one day.
See you soon.
Master Wong, knock on the door
when you are tired.
We stay up quite late.
- Thank you.
- Take care.
- Orchid...
- I know, you're going for the boy.
The officers won't look after him.
Take the medicine box. It will help.
I'm thirsty, some water, please.
Shut up!
Why does this child sleep
the whole day long?
Is he OK?
Does he need to see a doctor?
Whoever loses has to drink.
Master Fox...
Open the gate.
Wong Pei-hung, you have a visitor.
His forehead is hot and his mouth
is dry, Dr Yang. I think he is sick.
He can't stay here any more.
It's lucky we discovered it now.
Many people have caught the plague.
The plague?
It's not that bad, don't panic.
We're not panicking,
we're just afraid.
The investigator will arrive
in the next two days.
I can't take care of him.
Master Fox, conditions here are
appalling. Let him stay in my house.
Sorry to trouble you.
Don't start anything
or I'll punish you!
We won't cause any trouble.
We're happy you're moving him.
Dad's umbrella.
Master Wong!
- Come over for a midnight snack.
- OK.
Having a hotpot on the roof
makes it taste even nicer.
I've never done it before.
- Help yourself.
- All right.
Master Fox, thank you
for looking after my son.
Master Wong, if you can't catch
Iron Monkey on time,
I'll work something out
so you and your son can leave.
Don't worry.
But you might get in trouble.
I may be a bad official,
but I can protect myself.
A hero should be respected.
Hero?
People hold thieves up as heroes.
In fact, we are all just water
in the pot,
heated by the burning fire.
If the fire keeps burning,
the water will dry up.
Who can put out the fire?
When will we get good officials?
Damn it! Who's blocking the chimney?
Iron Monkey?
Hey! Wait for me!
Which one of you is Iron Monkey?
I am Master Fox,
you are under arrest.
Kidnap a woman? A rapist?
- The Shaolin Palm?
- You practise Shaolin Kung Fu.
- So what?
- Are you Shaolin apprentices?
A monk?
No Shadow Kick!
- The Super Eagle's Claw!
- Your master is the monk, Hin Hung.
You are a Shaolin rebel.
Dad, look out.
Here comes Iron Monkey.
Be careful.
Fei-hung.
It's you.
Tell Dad I'm OK.
The old one
worries about the young one.
The young one
worries about the old one.
Such a caring father and son.
I know who you are.
What did he say?
Ask him when he wakes up.
Difficult to distinguish you
A face of weariness
It's difficult to predict my fate
Orchid, Peony,
come and greet the guests.
My son.
It's time to see clients again.
It's been nine months. Get ready.
How dare you stab me!
Bitch!
I want to redeem Miss Ho.
Take the three gold pieces.
Willows and flowers follow the wind
A doctor cares
for patients from all parts
Maybe for the fulfillment
of our commitment
Count the fortune of your life
You go that way and you go that way.
How can you mess up
in the Governor's house?
Shit! Where is the Governor?
Hold it...
You want to see His Excellency.
Do you have an appointment?
Idiot!
Does the investigator need one?
Use the royal fan
to hit these bastards.
The royal fan?
Looks like this place
hasn't changed much.
I didn't see you on my last patrol.
- Are you new?
- I've been here two years now.
Did you check his identification?
I didn't dare, I'm only a junior.
Stop moving. I'm getting all wet!
Give me a kiss.
Turn your head.
How can I fix it
while you move about so much?
Do a good job for me.
Who are you?
You knew I was coming.
Look at the time.
How can you play in such a way?
Your Excellency.
Get the documents.
Come and see me once you are dressed.
Yes, sir.
I'm a busy man. Don't waste my time.
The royal fan?
Isn't that the royal fan?
I had the pleasure
of being hit with it.
Have you seen his royal seal?
I'm only a junior, I dared not ask.
Idiot. Help me get dressed.
How can you be Governor?
These documents are a mess!
Please forgive me, sir.
- Pick them up.
- Yes, sir.
May I see the royal seal?
You can't have done this job long.
Don't you know who I am?
Bring me my briefcase.
Where are my papers?
What's this?
Iron Monkey?
Iron Monkey? What is it?
He is a notorious criminal.
He commits all sorts
of horrible crimes.
This is ridiculous!
I didn't blame you
for not keeping the peace,
but how can you allow thieves
in this house?
How can you be Governor?
Please forgive me.
How can my official seal
turn into a monkey?
"HONESTY AND JUSTICE FOR ALL"
Court in session!
They look innocent, but in reality
they may be that vicious Iron Monkey!
Confess now!
- Who stole the seal?
- Hand it over!
Don't act so innocent in front of me.
Your Excellency, I think...
I'm a kind-hearted official.
I love my citizens.
But you can't be soft
with these guys!
He sounds familiar to me.
You always say that. It proves
you come from the same class.
You won't confess?
Then I must teach you a lesson.
Very wise. Give them a warning.
Fox!
I know it's you.
Give Governor Cheng 30 lashes!
Sir, it's an order. I can't help it.
Go ahead!
Enough! Enough!
I have an idea, sir, please...
Tell me, then.
Get lost!
Your Excellency, I hope
these documents are sufficient.
You're smart to come up with
this idea in such a short time.
Come here, come on.
Again, Your Excellency?
Sir...
It's a shame to see a smart guy
like you wasting away in this place.
Thank you, sir.
I'll deploy you to another province.
- Choose for yourself.
- Choose myself?
I'll choose a wealthy place.
I'm going to be rich!
It's worth being hit.
You return first
and organise my trip.
Yes, sir.
- Governor Cheng.
- Yes, sir.
Open the stores and donate the food
to the public. This will look good.
I'll report to the Emperor.
Thank you, sir.
Go on, open the stores
and hand out the food.
Hurry up.
Put the food on the cart.
Quickly, we must deliver it.
Next month, I'll be moving to Canton.
Would you give me some advice, sir?
As an officer you've observed four
righteous rules and four witty rules.
The four righteous rules are
to repay for merits,
to flatter, to liaise and to ally.
Anyone who is skilled in applying
these rules will be prosperous.
And the four witty rules?
To create discord, to reprobate,
to frame and to set others up.
How wise you are.
You have my greatest respect.
You've already learnt how to flatter.
I didn't mean to.
Just remember
politics is like a dream.
Don't take it too seriously
and you'll be fine.
Then you'll live long and prosper.
Prepare the sedan chair
for His Excellency.
Chiretta, good for blood.
Ginseng for respiration.
Crocodile to cure catarrh.
Lizard to treat poisoning.
Tin-tsi... tin-tsi...
You fool! Don't hit me, Dad!
Dad.
Stick out your tongue.
Come on, stick out your tongue.
A slight fever.
Dr Yang isn't here.
I'll give you some medicine.
If the fever doesn't subside,
come and see Dr Yang.
Thank you, Miss Ho.
"I've borrowed the pills
to raise money for my trip.
I must save my dad.
I'll repay you in the future."
Thank you.
Thank you for watching.
Ladies and gentlemen,
my father and I were separated
and I need money to get home.
I've no choice but to sell
our secret family life-saving pill.
30 taels each.
Little master, you helped us before,
now we'll help you.
Get lost!
Your dad hurt us before, kid.
Now it's our turn to hurt you.
Honest people don't do
sneaky things.
- I'm Wong Fei-hung. And you?
- Chiu Tin Pa.
Run, Wong Fei-hung!
After him!
Make way!
You piece of shit!
Bullying a small boy.
You have no future.
Your mother would rather
have a bun than you.
- Nice moves. Well done!
- Thank you.
Watch out, hot water!
Watch out yourself!
You ruined my stuff.
You little bastard!
Turn around.
Give me that.
Boss, I'll pay for the damages.
- Enough?
- More than enough.
Too much.
How come my Kung Fu is so good?
Wong Fei-hung, you are great...
Do you take students?
I'm not qualified to teach you.
Put me down.
Shut up!
Who is Wong Fei-hung?
That's me.
That's him.
A dragon? A worm, more like!
Call someone bigger than you.
I'm this big. If you want me
to be bigger, wait a few years.
Challenge me?
I specialise in taming small kids.
You're so powerful.
If I catch you, you will suffer.
Come and get me. You can't keep up.
Let's go for a run.
You're like a lump of wood.
Can't you keep up?
If I can't beat you, I'll retire.
I beat you. Retire.
He's really retired so quickly?
That was easy.
- Little worm.
- Crazy nut, another nasty show?
I've got thick skin.
- Stop talking to him.
- Shut up! He was lucky. Get lost.
Who hit me?
A stone.
Fei-hung, get up.
Come on.
Why did you sneak away?
I'm sorry, Auntie.
I wanted to find my dad.
I'll think of a way. Let's go.
"THE EMPEROR'S ROYAL OFFICERS"
Welcome, Your Excellency.
Summon the Governor.
Summon the Governor!
Summon me?
Is the investigator back again?
Where does this monk come from?
You dare sit in my chair? Take him
away and close down the temple.
Why don't you come to greet
the investigator?
You're the investigator?
Another one.
This time I've got to see
your royal seal.
My rule is to kill
before investigating.
Is that another note
from Iron Monkey?
We've no money left.
He is the real one.
Your Excellency.
So you'll serve me now?
Yes, sir! Wash all the dishes
and prepare a banquet.
Yes, sir.
His Excellency would like
some chicken and shark fin.
Of course, of course.
The rod is blind,
it sweeps away all injustice.
Strong force
that switches north and south.
Fei-hung, your turn.
Seek the way.
Fisherman's Paddle!
Double Flight from the Sea!
Old Branches on the Ground!
Open Both Up and Down!
Rod that Calms the Central!
- Is he your first apprentice?
- You are the first.
He is your junior.
His dad will fight with you
sooner or later.
I really hope he doesn't come.
If you lose...
That's why I'm teaching him
how to use the rod.
At least I get a follower.
Come on, Fei-hung.
Dad!
They should meet each other.
- Thank you.
- My pleasure.
Still in one piece.
Dad, don't worry.
A man should be dignified.
Fei-hung hasn't made you lose face.
Good. I'm glad you've grown up.
My worries are over.
Thank you for saving my son Fei-hung.
My pleasure.
Please...
Help yourselves.
I heard there were some refugees
coming into town.
Iron Monkey will be around then.
Fei-hung, take this.
Fei-hung! No.
You can't eat roast duck,
you're ill. Let go.
From my diagnosis
he shouldn't eat so much.
You have it, Dr Yang.
You don't need a special diet
with my medicines.
It's better to be safe than sorry.
The Po Chi Lam Clinic prescription
is quite effective.
Fei-hung is still young, his stomach
is too weak to take such greasy food.
Brother Wong, you'd not put it
this way. But there is a basic law.
Since he's just recovered, he has
no appetite. This will give him one.
It doesn't matter what he eats,
as long as he does.
Not at all.
You'll never finish your meal
if you keep arguing.
I'm sorry.
THE GOVERNMENT HOUSE
OF CHEKIANG
It's nice to be so relaxed about
things. You still have your women...
I'd love to be a monk like you.
What a waste of my talent.
Goodbye sweet ladies.
The dream has faded.
I must get some money
to buy an officer's post.
My last prayers, I can't believe
I have to bury you here.
Bless me
that I won't be tortured in future.
After I've buried you,
I'll have to sell myself.
Protect my future descendants from
such suffering as I've experienced.
You don't have to sell yourself.
Take this money
and bury your husband.
- Thank you.
- My pleasure.
Dead monkey, I'll bury you!
It's a trap.
Right.
A rich city merchant hired us.
You'd better surrender,
Iron Monkey, or else.
You impostors!
I'll remove your mask.
You bastards.
You're even worse
than those greedy officers.
The Virgin's Sword Stance.
How can you call yourself a virgin?
You're so ugly,
you look more like a pig!
Lo Han's Double-Edged Sword!
You don't know one side of the sword
from the other!
Take your hands off!
Why don't you leave?
You call yourselves martial artists?
You have to beat me too
before you leave.
Shaolin King Kong Palm.
Your Kung Fu is good. You even
recognise my Shaolin King Kong Palm.
It's nothing special.
Then try my Nothing Special move.
You can't escape from me.
Iron Monkey?
Shaolin Palm?
The Flying Monk?
Right, I'm the master
of the Flying Monk.
Monk, you rebelled against Shaolin.
It was you who burnt
the Shaolin Temple.
There are no rules. Human beings
die for fortune. Birds die for feed!
Preach to your dead colleagues.
How dare you challenge me.
- Tell me your name.
- Wong Kei-ying.
Wong Kei-ying, your Kung Fu
is like nothing I've seen before.
You're right.
No Shadow Kick, the Wong family move.
King Kong Palm!
You don't know when to give up.
I might as well finish you off!
Wind and Thunder King Kong Palm!
Lo Han Palm!
Once you've felt my King Kong Palm,
you've no chance of survival.
Are you OK?
Where are you hurt?
Get the needles for me.
I was hit by the King Kong Palm.
Release the poisoned blood first,
then give me the antidote.
Release the blood.
Take down the list of medicines now.
One centipede.
The tail of a scorpion.
The gall of a bear.
One viper.
One lizard...
Big brother, wake up!
Any other medicines?
Wake up.
Dr Yang!
Dad, are you OK?
Fei-hung, Dad is hurt,
get Dr Yang now.
Who is he?
Iron Monkey?
Dad!
- What are you doing, Fei-hung?
- Stop, Dad, he isn't Iron Monkey.
How dare you contradict your father?
Master Wong.
Is Dr Yang Iron Monkey?
Dad!
I just want to inspect
Dr Yang's wound.
Silly boy!
Miss Orchid, please get up.
King Kong Palm?
"Fight poison with poison.
It's a valuable treatment."
What an excellent doctor he is.
- Fei-hung, get a pen and ink ready.
- Yes, Dad.
There are no norms and no rules
You are trapped in a corner
There is nowhere to run
- Gold can't change
- Sad for blood
Release the blood
and revitalise the soul
A curse that would put you to death
- Emergency aid
- One chance for life
The only way out is death
Hurry up! Cure him.
Dad!
Iron Monkey and Wong Kei-ying
are both hurt.
Check all the clinics.
Arrest all those who are hurt!
Yes, sir!
Such medicines can cure
all sorts of illnesses.
Po Chi Lam Clinic
is really prestigious.
To cure poison
with poisonous insects.
The impact of your clinic on medicine
in the future will be enormous.
However, will you take me to court?
I can't right now,
but you will be arrested one day.
Take my advice and mend your ways.
My father was a righteous officer
when Wei Zhou was deposed.
His colleagues were greedy
and stole food.
My father was killed because of them.
How can the officers save others
when they can't even save themselves?
You can even buy an officer's post.
If there were fewer greedy officers
in the world,
we wouldn't need Iron Monkey.
- Who is it?
- Master Fox.
- Where is Dr Yang?
- He is out.
- Where is Wong Fei-hung?
- He's with Dr Yang.
Damn it!
The investigator wants them arrested.
Why?
Tell them to leave immediately.
Master Wong...
I heard.
I can't believe
they're going to arrest me.
Dad, let's leave now.
Fei-hung, you can't follow me,
it's very dangerous.
Go back to Fushan by yourself.
If I don't return...
you take care of yourself.
Yes, Dad.
Fei-hung, a man
should be as strong as steel.
I understand.
A man should shed blood, not tears.
- Do you understand?
- Don't worry, Dad.
Dr Yang, please look after my dad.
If anything happens,
please let me know.
Of course.
Dad, don't worry about me.
Fei-hung, have you
forgotten my words already?
Don't cry!
Repeat what I said before.
A man should be as strong as steel.
A man should shed blood, not tears.
Master Wong,
I'll show you the back way out.
- We'll find a safe hiding place.
- Fine.
Dad.
Don't worry,
I'll take care of Fei-hung.
Fei-hung, go inside. I'll answer it.
- Open the door!
Open up!
A girl! A pretty girl.
What do you want? Aren't you monks
ashamed of yourselves?
A monk still needs pretty girls.
Let's enjoy ourselves.
Do you want our lives to be empty?
The Tum Ma move?
She knows Kung Fu. There's something
strange about this clinic.
Stranger than you?
I'll show you!
Ether powder.
We got her.
Look at that face.
She's so attractive.
Let's listen to her screams.
We'll do our best to entertain you.
I guarantee a pleasant surprise.
We'll help ourselves.
See how nervous she is.
She must be very anxious.
Relax, this won't take long.
Go to hell, you bastard monks!
Monks aren't monks,
officers aren't officers. Bullshit!
You little bastard,
do you want to die?
Auntie, leave now!
Do you want to go in?
Carry the Bow and Shoot the Moon!
Monkey's Rod!
Double Flight from the Sea!
Fisherman's Paddle!
What are you reciting?
Too many stances.
Don't let his stances put you off.
Rod that Sweeps Away all Injustice!
Very powerful.
Strong Force
that Switches North and South!
Don't let him recite. No more!
Over the Top...
Under the Earth!
Stop for a minute.
I don't think so.
Let's see you dance.
Left, right, left, right,
left, right. Halt!
Golden Snake Goes Into the Hole,
Golden Snake Comes Out of the Hole!
Back to the start.
Old witch!
Are you trying to scare the ghosts?
Then you can be a ghost.
No Shadow Kick!
Iron Monkey is Buddha.
The gold which he gave us
can't be spent frivolously.
If we spend it all
there won't be any more.
Dr Yang, Master Wong,
dinner is ready. Let's eat.
Thank you.
There are only two bowls.
What about you?
We have a big abalone.
Don't lie to us.
We'll have the big abalone,
you take the rice.
Well, we'll share
these bowls of rice.
We've already eaten. Here.
I don't even like rice.
- We've eaten. Here.
- I don't like rice.
Miss Ho is here.
Big brother, Fei-hung's been arrested
by the soldiers.
What?
What's wrong with you?
Orchid, Orchid!
It must be the monks. Orchid!
She seems to be suffering
from ether poisoning. Orchid!
Wake her up first.
Wong Fei-hung,
tell us where your father is.
Your dad is here.
Greet him now. Damn baldy!
Tough guy, I'll teach you
a lesson you won't forget.
Wait! If we kill him,
we'll never find Wong Kei-ying.
You're a traitor!
How dare you beat me,
the head of security!
Master Fox!
Look out!
Hin Hung, let Wong Fei-hung go.
You're not the Iron Monkey I met.
Iron Monkey is Iron Monkey.
Hin Hung, prepare to meet your death!
Iron Monkey is here.
Catch Fei-hung!
The Flying Sleeves!
Come here!
Wong Kei-ying or Iron Monkey,
you still have to die!
Kill them both!
Go to hell!
See the Dart!
- You can't save him now.
- Have pity.
You've come to help.
You must all be in the same gang!
Call yourself a Kung Fu master?
You're useless!
Don't block my way.
Be gone!
Take Fei-hung away.
Your Excellency! Your Excellency!
Take him away.
Flying Sleeves?
What happened to Shaolin Palm?
You didn't die from my palm?
You're tough, huh?
You are an investigator
yet you yourself are underhand.
You are a disgrace
to your profession!
Let's fight, then!
Hurry up!
Stay where you are!
I'll be a laughing stock
if I let you bastards escape!
Old traitor, let's see how many
stances you can resist.
You joined forces with Iron Monkey
and brought shame on our school.
You have no right
to call me a traitor.
Stop pretending to be so righteous.
If it weren't for bastards like you,
there wouldn't be
a need for Iron Monkey!
Flying Sleeves!
Come here!
The Fifth Brother's Rod!
Old traitor!
Come on.
Shaolin King Kong Palm!
- No Shadow Kick!
- Flying Leg!
I'm coming! Damn you, baldy!
Fei-hung, don't! It's too dangerous.
Up the poles.
Hey! It's burning. Get down.
The fire is burning the poles.
Dad! Iron Monkey! Run!
Hin Hung, I can't defeat you on
the ground, but your balance is bad.
- I'll beat you on the poles.
- Well, come on then.
Let me take your place.
Watch out!
Off the poles.
Not good enough.
Attack the lower part. I'll go first.
No Shadow Kick!
Hit him!
King Kong Falls!
You're no better.
Shaolin King Kong Palm!
Iron Monkey, catch!
Monkey Hangs on the Dried Tree!
Push him down! The monk is losing.
Not so easy!
A Thousand Hand Move!
Kick him off!
Hit him!
Fall down!
It's hooked.
When the wooden poles burn,
we'll have to fight in the fire.
Down, dog!
Stay where you are.
A return for you, monk!
I'll sweep away all the poles.
Iron Monkey, over here!
There's only one pole left,
you're going to fall!
It's going!
Stand at the two ends.
You can't stand properly.
Don't worry about us.
The pole under your feet
won't last much longer.
You'll be buried in this sea of fire.
Kick the pole and push me across.
- The door is open.
- One pole to the sky.
Monk, we tricked you.
One pole to the sea!
You are totally wicked.
Down to the fire!
- Hurry up! Throw the rod here.
- OK!
Catch!
Dad.
I'm fine.
I thought I was
never going to see you again.
Why doesn't anybody care about me?
Don't just stand there, leave now.
Go!
TRAIN STATION
Master Wong,
who knows when we'll meet again?
Dr Yang, Miss Ho, why don't you come
to Fushan to visit us?
Auntie, you must come.
Master Wong, I'm sorry I'm late.
Ah, you've come to see us off
though you're so busy.
Don't mention it.
I'm busy catching Iron Monkey.
Another new officer is coming.
I hope he is a good one.
Well, we must say goodbye.
Fei-hung, let's go.
Take care.
Let me step out onto the wide road
And head towards
a bright and promising future
Young as I am,
I'm full of energy and talent
I have a lot of dreams and
I will make them all come true
I will have my glory in the future
out in the world...